SEPIDEH AYANI

3116 W. Lake St. Unit 218 Minneapolis, MN 55416 sepid.ayani@gmail.com (C) 651.890.9173

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Highly motivated, hardworking, analytical, and passionate Software Engineer with concentration in Data Management/Big Data. Seeking to apply my expertise and five years of experience to develop tools that will help teams at Target organize and analyze large amounts of data to identify patterns and trends that can be used to highlight business opportunities and make informed decisions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- O/S: Mac
- Languages: Java/SpringBoot, JavaScript/React
- Database: Postgres, MongoDB
- Tools: IntelliJ IDEA, Atom, Visual Studio, MS Office
- Cloud: Experienced with Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Familiar with: MongoDB/NoSQL, Python, R, Grafana, Kibana, Hadoop, Kafka, Jenkins, REST APIs and Docker

WORK EXPERIENCE

Target Sep 2019 – Present

Software Engineer

- Using Java/SpringBoot to support the backend application by adding scalable functionalities
- Using JavaScript/React to make the UI more user friendly by adding new features
- Use Python to train Google machine learning models to identify shortages at self-checkout registers
- Use YOLO real-time object detection system to train machine learning models to track individual items through flatbed scanners and self-checkout registers
- Build and maintain a visualization user interface that enables asset protection team members to track and identify asset shortages at individual stores
- Build visualization dashboard using Grafana
- Build CI/CD pipeline for project using in-house tools
- Contribute to writing technical documents for future references
- On boarding new interns to the team and setting up training courses to set them to succussed

Software Engineer

- Collaborated with team of ten developers to build and maintain a legal document research platform called Westlaw Edge, which was comprised of over 1600 datasets and more than 2.2 billion active documents, running in two live production big data environments
- Built visualization dashboards using Kibana and Grafana
- Built CI/CD pipeline for project using Jenkins
- Served as a Diversity and Inclusion Champion for the entire Department of Technology

PhData

Jan 2016 – Aug 2016

Solutions Engineer Intern

- Worked closely with architects and engineers to collect, normalize, and transform data from various sources into big data solutions
- Built live Twitter data streaming API for a specific hashtag (#NationalInternDay) using Java
- Partnered with senior leadership team to present PhData big data management solutions to multiple companies

EDUCATION

University of St. Thomas, MN

Master of Science, Computer Software Engineering

2013 - 2016

- Concentration: Data Management / Big Data
- Awards: International Women Scholarship

Universiti Malaya, Kuala Lumpur

2010 - 2012

Master of Science, Business Administration

Islamic Azad University, Tehran

2003 - 2007

Bachelor's Degree, Business Administration and Management